Eikaiwa Time Trial
Let's get started with Day 1 for the month of September.
Hi everyone! I'm Steve Zareisi.
And I'm Jenny Skidmore. Thanks for joining us.
It's a new month of Eikaiwa Time Trial.
今年度のテーマは英語でつながる船の旅。
毎月異なる国や地域をクルーズ船に乗って巡ります。
And starting this month, we are going to Scotland!
今月はイギリス・グレート・ブリッテン島の北に位置するスコットランドを訪れます。
そして金曜日はこの方がスコットランドの旅へと誘ってくれます。
Welcome to Scotland!
I'm your conversation partner, Nora.
On Friday, let's go to a famous lake in Scotland.
The autumn leaves are beautiful, but we need to dress warmly.
See you then.
Thanks, Nora.
A famous lake in Scotland.
In this fall season, that sounds beautiful.
そして最後に言ってましたね。
You need to dress warmly.
今月の学習テーマはこちら。
Dress for success in Scotland.
スコットランドを舞台に服にまつわる表現を身につけていきましょう。
では、SPRトレーニングから始めます。
今回はマフラー、セーターなど衣類にまつわる文を練習しましょう。
では、1回目の挑戦です。
どれくらい言えるか力でメッシュをしましょう。
OK, it's time for your...
First Try!
S.P.R. Training
では僕の言う日本語を時間内に英語で表現してください
一つ目
温かい服がいります
英語でどうぞ
スキーウェアしかありません
どうぞ
ジャケットを持ってきましたか?
Did you から言ってみよう。
どうぞ。
いいえ、でもセーターを持ってきました。
今日マフラーを持ってきましたか?
Let's look at the two sentences that will be the answer to this question.
It's supposed to be.
Let's check it.
Did you bring an umbrella?
Before we move on to the next sentence, let's check this expression.
折りたたみ傘 折りたたみ傘 折りたたみ傘 is 折りたたみ傘 in English.
The recommended word is foldable umbrella, or compact umbrella.
Foldable is similar to foldable in Japanese, so let's use this sentence.
I brought a folding umbrella.
Now, before we move on to the last sentence, let's check this vowel.
雨の時に着るカッパを英語で言うと?
答えはレインパンチョー。
レインコート、レインジャケットよりもレインパンチョーを使ってこの文を言ってみよう。
野球の試合でカッパを買いました。
Okay, how was your first round? Did you try to say each one?
では、ここで回答例をチェックしましょう。
Now you can check your answers with mine. Listen closely.
温かい服がいります。
We need warm clothes.
主語をweにしましたか?
相手にアドバイスあるいは注意するときに主語をweにして、
Anata mo watashi mo atatakai fuku ga irimasu.
We need warm clothes.
Sa, tsugi desu.
Ski wear shika arimasen.
I only have ski clothes.
Nihongo datto sports wear ya training wear nado iimasu ga.
Eigo no wear wa kihontekiri doushi to shite tsukaimasu.
Ifuku wo arawasu teiba no meishi wa clothes.
クローズのつづりから発音がクローゼスと思ってしまうかもしれないんですが、
そうではなくて、閉じるのクローズと同じ。
クローズ。
ですので、スキーウェアのことはスキークローズになります。
さあ、次です。
ジャケットを持ってきましたか?
Did you bring a jacket?
いいえ、でもセーターを持ってきました。
No, but I brought a sweater.
セーターのことはスウェーダー。
OK, the next one has マフラー。
Here it is.
今日、マフラーを持ってきましたか?
Did you bring a scarf today?
たまにそのままマフラーを言う人もいますが、
車の部品、マフラーと混乱しやすいので、
スカーフが一般的になってきました。
マフラーを言いたいときにこのように、
Did you bring a scarf today?
さあ、次です。
そのはずです。確認します。
I think so. I'll check.
日本語のそのはずですを英語で言うのに、
I think so.と言い換えても大丈夫です。
そうだと思いますが、そのはずです。
I think so.
自分にとって言いやすいし、相手にとって確実に伝わります。
さあ、次です。
傘を持ってきましたか?
Did you bring an umbrella?
Oritatami no kasa o motte kimashita.
I brought a foldable umbrella.
Yakkyu no shiai de kappa o kaimashita.
I bought a rain poncho at the baseball game.
Okay, did you understand today's phrases?
それではみなさん、今学習した表現をテンポよくもう一度言ってみましょう。
We'll pick up the pace a little in round two. Here we go!
温かい服がいります。
We need warm clothes.
スキーウェアしかありません。
I only have ski clothes.
ジャケットを持ってきましたか?
Did you bring a jacket?
いいえ、でもセーターを持ってきました。
No, but I brought a sweater.
今日、マフラーを持ってきましたか?
Did you bring a scarf today?
Sono hazu desu. Kakunin shimasu.
I think so. I'll check.
Kasa wo motte kimashita ka?
Did you bring an umbrella?
Oritatami no kasa wo motte kimashita.
I brought a foldable umbrella.
野球の試合でカッパを買いました。
I bought a rain poncho at the baseball game.
Okay, time's up.
Well, how was your second try?
We're talking about warm clothes.
And you'll have warm feelings if you practice hard together with Jenny and I.
Great job today.
So everyone, get on board.
And let's practice speaking together.
See you next time on...
Ekaewa Time Trial.
Bye-bye.